PETER PAKER

Full Stack Developer

@ peterpaker0325@gmail.com

Calgary, AB, Canada

SUMMARY

A Full Stack Developer with **9 years of experience** driving performance, reliability and scalability of customer-facing web applications. Effectively led full stack development resulting in 25% faster loading times and improved user experience. Deployed applications to multiple cloud-based production environments, set up and maintained a relational database system, integrated third-party services and created web-based CMSs resulting in quicker information and feature updates.

EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Developer

11/2021 - 4/2023

I-star

- Led full stack development for a customer-facing web application, resulting in 25% faster loading times and an improved UX/UI.
- Optimized application performance by identifying and refactoring inefficient code, resulting in a 20% increase in speed.
- Deployed applications on multiple cloud-based production environments and maintained staging environments for testing, resulting in a 30% increase in code quality.
- Implemented automated tests and test suites, reducing the number of bugs by 30% and improving overall code quality by 25%.

Web Applications Developer

04/2019 - 11/2021

Pason Systems

- Optimization web services and APIs that enabled seamless communication between front-end and back-end components, enhancing performance by 20%.
- Set up a relational database manager for storage, retrieval, and manipulation of data, leading to improved data accessibility by 30%.
- Utilized source control, automation tools, and CI/CD processes to improve product life cycles and optimize production releases speed by 25%.
- Developed databases and data storage solutions, improving data retrieval times by 40% and reducing data loss by 50%.
- Collaborated with the UX team to optimize the user experience, resulting in a 15% increase in customer satisfaction scores.

Junior Full Stack Developer

10/2016 - 04/2019

PureWeb

- Integrated a wide range of third-party services and components like payment gateways, geo-location services, and social media logins.
- QA of a monitoring and alerting program, resulting in a 90% reduction in downtime and a 80% reduction in incident response time.
- Monitored system health, debugged performance issues, and optimized applications, resulting in a 25% increase in code quality.
- Identified and addressed software security issues, resulting in a 40% reduction in security vulnerabilities and a 30% increase in security.

Researcher

11/2014 - 10/2016

University of Calgary

- Integrated Stripe API into a React progressive web app (PWA) to purchase digital services.
- Designed custom solutions for clients from multiple industries, including oil and gas, education, emergency response, and health services.

EDUCATION

Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science

University of Calgary - Calgary, Alberta, Canada

10/2010 - 11/2014

SKILLS

Client-Side

HTML5 · CSS3 · JavaScript · TypeScript ·

 $React \cdot MUI \cdot Bootstrap \cdot Redux \cdot$

UI/UX Design

Server-Side

Python · Node.js · Django · TensorFlow ·

JSP · Flask · ElasticSearch · SQL · Oracle ·

MongoDB

Development & Operation

Agile · scrum · Git · JUnit

STRENGTH

Agile Methodology
Proficient

Software Quality Analysis Proficient

Software Design Pattern Proficient

Project Management Advanced

d

LANGUAGES

Chinese

English

Japanese